Ain't it just like the night
to play tricks when you're
tryin' to be so quiet?
We sit here stranded,
though we're all doin'
our best to deny it
And Louise holds a handful
of rain, temptin' you to defy it
Lights flicker from
the opposite loft
In this room the heat pipes
just cough
The country music station
plays soft
But there's nothing,
really nothing to turn off
Just Louise and her lover
so entwined
And these visions of Johanna
that conquer my mind
In the empty lot
where the ladies play
blindman's bluff
with the key chain
And the all-night girls
they whisper of escapades
out on the "D" train
We can hear the night watchman
click his flashlight
Ask himself if it's him
or them that's insane
Louise, she's all right,
she's just near
She's delicate and
seems like the mirror
But she just makes it all too
concise and too clear
That Johanna's not here
The ghost of 'lectricity howls
in the bones of her face
Where these visions of Johanna
have now taken my place
Now, little boy lost,
he takes himself so seriously
He brags of his misery,
he likes to live dangerously
And when bringing her name up
He speaks of a farewell
kiss to me
He's sure got a lotta gall
to be so useless and all
Muttering small talk at the wall
while I'm in the hall
How can I explain?
It's so hard to get on
And these visions of Johanna,
they kept me up past the dawn
Inside the museums,
infinity goes up on trial
Voices echo this is what
salvation must be like
after a while
But Mona Lisa musta had
the highway blues
You can tell by the way
she smiles
See the primitive
wallflower freeze
When the jelly-faced women
all sneeze
Hear the one with the mustache
say, "Jeez, I can't find my
knees"
Oh, jewels and binoculars
hang from the head of the mule
But these visions of Johanna,
they make it all seem so cruel
The peddler now speaks
to the countess who's
pretending to care for him
Sayin', "Name me someone that's
not a parasite and I'll go out
and say a prayer for him"
But like Louise always says
"Ya can't look at much,
can ya man?"
As she, herself,
prepares for him
And Madonna,
she still has not showed
We see this empty cage
now corrode
Where her cape of the
stage once had flowed
The fiddler,
he now steps to the road
He writes ev'rything's been
returned which was owed
On the back of the
fish truck that loads
While my conscience explodes
The harmonicas play
the skeleton keys and the rain
And these visions of Johanna
are now all that remain